[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339755", "question": "Who played Sam Spade in the 1941 movie \"The Maltese Falcon\"?", "answer": "Humphrey Bogart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3de", "question": "What city is the capital of Turkey?", "answer": "Ankara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c5d49076251badbead2", "question": "What year gave birth to the word \"motel\"?", "answer": "The term \"motel\" originated with the\u00a0Milestone Mo-Tel, which was constructed in 1925 by Arthur Heineman.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e8", "question": "What surname for John in \"The Importance of Being Earnest\" did Oscar Wilde take from the seaside town he vacationed at?", "answer": "Worthing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb1", "question": "Which fruit is used to make Calvados?\u00a0", "answer": "Apples\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a17a", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Next\"?", "answer": "The Sensational Alex Harvey Band", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedd8b06ce05a3942286d73", "question": "The Soup Nazi was an infamous character on which sitcom?", "answer": "\"Seinfeld\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eae31f83302ff91e46486", "question": "What animal was the Egyptian God Horus depicted as?", "answer": "Falcon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601370631381754895396381", "question": "In the 1990 film \"Home Alone\", Joe Pesci's character, Harry Lime, was named after\u00a0a character from\u00a0which Orson Welles' film?", "answer": "The Third Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b780", "question": "What city's Summer Olympics had the beaver Amik as their mascot?", "answer": "Montreal's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d0", "question": "Which bar is the Grasshopper cocktail is said to have originated from?", "answer": "Tujague's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecce80ec223966ae8f88b0", "question": "Who did not attend the 1977 premiere of \"Star Wars: A New Hope\"?", "answer": "George Lucas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a70e", "question": "What city in Ohio is known as the \"rubber capital of the US\"?", "answer": "Akron", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca2b", "question": "What is James Dewar most famous for inventing?", "answer": "The vacuum flask", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe25717658e585fda9cfa3a", "question": "What destructive party item was banned in Hollywood on Halloween starting in 2004?", "answer": "Silly String", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c72f", "question": "In the Steve Miller song \"The Joker\", what men\u2019s name do \"some people call him\"?", "answer": "Maurice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e6c", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Daredevil\"?", "answer": "Ben Affleck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339377", "question": "How many Oscars did the 1997 movie \"Titanic\" win?", "answer": "11", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf2b", "question": "What is sometimes known as Goober Grease?", "answer": "Peanut Butter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60173fab44491cbd7c5a17b4", "question": "What general commanded the American Expeditionary Forces on the Western Front during World War I?", "answer": "John Joseph \"Black Jack\" Pershing GCB", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133980e", "question": "What was rapper Eminem's first album titled?", "answer": "Infinite", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e94d0b65ea27d7a1303aed2", "question": "In a standard deck of cards, which of the face cards are the only ones whose hair is colored in a deck of playing cards?", "answer": "Jacks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9aa", "question": "What do you call three under par in golf?", "answer": "Albatross or double eagle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a25f1376682715b82711cdd", "question": "What decade did Gene Autry star in the Western musical \"Melody Ranch\"?", "answer": "1940s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab1b7fbaab681b0929219a", "question": "What is BMW's name short for?", "answer": "Bayerische Motoren Werke", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339345", "question": "What real-life family was the inspiration for the TV show \"Partridge Family\"?", "answer": "The Cowsills", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b4", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Evergreen State\"?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c633", "question": "What are the twin stars in the constellation of Gemini called?", "answer": "Pollux and Castor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c789", "question": "The Earth's ozone layer absorbs what type of radiation from the Sun?", "answer": "Ultraviolet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b546", "question": "What is the first man-made object to circle the earth?", "answer": "Sputnik I", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f7", "question": "What was the first name of the cartoon character Mr. Magoo?", "answer": "Quincy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1f020145fb2946670738f", "question": "Popcorn comes in which two general shapes?", "answer": "Mushroom and butterfly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339619", "question": "Who was the lead singer for the band called the Police?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4fa", "question": "What two US state names end with the letter Y?", "answer": "Kentucky and New Jersey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e8", "question": "On what holiday did W. C. Fields die?", "answer": "Christmas Day", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8be1ec223966ae8f8844", "question": "Which television series revolves around a concierge doctor making house calls in the Hamptons?", "answer": "\"Royal Pains\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59c1cdb87bd84c0ea43ad42d", "question": "Which country borders Macedonia to the north?", "answer": "Serbia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b28501dd7bf43be5e79f", "question": "What does your moon sign represent?", "answer": "Your subconscious and emotions", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c77cc5c24f0f7a362efd53e", "question": "What is element is Wolfram?", "answer": "Tungsten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b013", "question": "Who was \"Time\" magazine's first \"person of the year\"?", "answer": "Charles Lindburgh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b9a", "question": "The Art Nouveau designer Rene Lalique worked with what material?", "answer": "Glass", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b241", "question": "What royal subject married Timothy Laurence?", "answer": "Princess Anne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b36e", "question": "What is Ronald Reagan's middle name?", "answer": "Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b323184bf195a31e15d7385", "question": "What cartoon featured a boy with a community of tiny people living in his wall?", "answer": "The Littles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e80464de59ea584496fea4", "question": "What are the names of the two adult Dalmatians in the novel \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "Pongo and Missis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe76643eec85e375820b27d", "question": "In which mountain range is the highest continuous paved road in the U.S.?", "answer": "Rocky Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c94d", "question": "What line on a map connects places of equal rainfall?", "answer": "Isohyet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "591c349c815febcc896f9253", "question": "On which of the Canary Island would you find the holiday destination of Corralejo?", "answer": "Fuerteventura", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133affa", "question": "What general led the Confederates at the Battle of Gettysburg?", "answer": "General Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d1", "question": "Who are the creators of the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Matt Stone and Trey Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba95", "question": "Who was the first football coach to win both a Rose Bowl in 1976 and a Super Bowl in 2000?", "answer": "Dick Vermeil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395bf", "question": "When the Simpsons go camping, where does Maggie spend her first night?", "answer": "With bears in a cave", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f3f5ff048f679a45aac5", "question": "What year was the fire extinguisher invented?", "answer": "1723", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59c1cefc7bd84c0ea43ad43d", "question": "\"The Obvious Child\" was a 1990 hit for whom?", "answer": "Paul Simon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067b7cff9c0647b50a8064", "question": "What 2009 first-person shooter game mostly takes place in 2016?", "answer": "Call of Duty: Modern Warfare 2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60173fea44491cbd7c5a17b8", "question": "The Battle of Austerlitz took place during which war?", "answer": "Napoleonic Wars", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae45", "question": "Of what nationality was the explorer Ponce de Leon?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cac0", "question": "What is the most abundant metal in Earth's core?", "answer": "Iron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef5ee66ce05a3942286e3b", "question": "Kyle Korver is frequently mistaken for which famous actor?", "answer": "Ashton Kutcher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa5446ce05a3942286ebc", "question": "In the film \"Airplane!\", what was the name of Leslie Nelson's character?", "answer": "Dr. Alan Rumack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fac", "question": "What TV title character lived at 485 Mapleton Drive, Mayfield?", "answer": "Beaver Cleaver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc1183469bb8041d07a075", "question": "In cooking, what is cutting herbs or vegetables into very fine strips called?", "answer": "Chiffonade", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b5a101dd7bf43be5e7d3", "question": "What is the term for the space between your eyebrows?", "answer": "Glabella", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd4", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"P\"?", "answer": "Papa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a4d990408b8581f80b092b2", "question": "What month in 2017 did North Korea fire a test missile across the Sea of Japan, prompting international condemnation?", "answer": "February", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339509", "question": "What is the name of John Carpenter's first feature movie?", "answer": "Dark Star", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a022", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", who is Stewie's half-brother and nemesis?", "answer": "Bertram", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b923", "question": "What car company was named for the founder of Detroit?", "answer": "Cadillac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c379", "question": "What name is given to male rhinoceroses?", "answer": "Bulls", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b233", "question": "St. Louis' Gateway Arch is officially named for what US president?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ec", "question": "Huntz Hall was a member of what comedic film group?", "answer": "The Bowery Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e9", "question": "Which \"Friends\" actress appeared in Bruce Springsteen's \"Dancing in the Dark\" video?", "answer": "Courtney Cox", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9d1", "question": "What is the capital of the US state North Carolina?", "answer": "Raleigh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c38f", "question": "What bird lays the largest eggs?", "answer": "The ostrich", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6bd", "question": "Which state is home to the third highest mountain peak in the US?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd96eb023c87fd04dd15e3b", "question": "What was the last land battle of the Civil War?", "answer": "Palmito Ranch", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600241d94be4723ccac2217e", "question": "In the book \"The Hunt for Red October,\" how is the Soviet submarine V. K. Konovalov destroyed?", "answer": "Reactor meltdown", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015f62afe83fe1f2a824c1c", "question": "During which period in Japanese history did \"Seven Samurai\" take place?", "answer": "Sengoku", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a16f", "question": "Which two popular movie stars were in the 1988 movie \"Mississippi Burning\"?", "answer": "Gene Hackman and Willem Dafoe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab18e2baab681b0929218f", "question": "Which car manufacturer produces the Clio?", "answer": "Renault", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339105", "question": "What city saw the debut of the 1875 opera \"Carmen\"?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b934", "question": "What color is the 3 ball in pool?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ab", "question": "Which film won an Oscar for Best Visual Effects in 1990?", "answer": "Total Recall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3589615db0d66a186cb54a", "question": "Which popular artist was born as Robyn Fenty in 1988 in Barbados?", "answer": "Rihanna", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a983", "question": "What legendary Arizona gold mine is named in honor of prospector Jacob Waltz?", "answer": "The Lost Dutchman mine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e805d2de59ea584496feac", "question": "Which town was severly damaged by the Boland Earthquake in September 1969?", "answer": "Tulbagh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e72ce4cd0874f1a5e2d1c27", "question": "Which prominent US statesman was known as \"The Great Compromiser\" and helped allegedly swing the 1824 election?", "answer": "Henry Clay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c382", "question": "What poisonous spider can be identified by a small red hourglass-shaped marking on the underside of its body?", "answer": "Black widow", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7352deec85e375820b246", "question": "Who was President Nixon's first vice president?", "answer": "Spiro T. Agnew", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a899b5d60d398dc9cf7a69c", "question": "Where is the Grand Canal?", "answer": "Venice", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cd85ee347d002c297e4c7", "question": "Who flew too close to the Sun??", "answer": "Icarus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133899e", "question": "In music, how should a section labeled as \"fortississimo\" be played?", "answer": "Loudest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a71", "question": "What is the name of the girl Bruce Springsteen is singing to in the song \"Born to Run\"?", "answer": "Wendy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339507", "question": "Who provides the voice for Abe Sapien in the 2004 movie \"Hellboy\"?", "answer": "David Hyde Pierce", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef60c26ce05a3942286e4b", "question": "Who won the first Academy Award for Best Actor ever presented?", "answer": "Emil Jannings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b40c", "question": "What was Banlgadesh formerly known as until its independence?", "answer": "East Pakistan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3fe", "question": "In land area, what is the largest country in South America?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988c", "question": "What Canadian television series did hip hop star Drake star as a main character?", "answer": "Degrassi: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f0", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince\", who does Harry catch tentacula leaves?", "answer": "Professor Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f91", "question": "What is Goldfinger's first name?", "answer": "Auric", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aed", "question": "What 1975 #1 song by Van McCoy spawned a dance craze of the same name?", "answer": "The Hustle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b996", "question": "In 1982, who began selling spaghetti sauce, turning over all profits to charity?", "answer": "Paul Newman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea47c3ff048f679a45abad", "question": "What strangely named type of mackerel is also known as an Ono in Hawaii?", "answer": "Wahoo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b9", "question": "What was the name of the debut single for the 1990's German band \"Snap!\"?", "answer": "The Power", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339144", "question": "What is the German title of Thomas Mann's novella \"Death in Venice\"?", "answer": "Der Tod in Venedig", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5d6", "question": "What is the name of the strait of water that separates the two main islands of New Zealand?", "answer": "Cook Strait", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3ccbff048f679a45ab43", "question": "What does the name \"lagomorph\" refer to?", "answer": "Rabbit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba6c", "question": "What round-bottomed cooking vessel did China introduce to the culinary world?", "answer": "The wok", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c896", "question": "Where did the world's tallest bird, the giant moa, live until it went extinct around 1500?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b03", "question": "Which character killed Elizabeth Vladimir Lensky?", "answer": "Eugene Onegin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133967f", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of the Springfield bowling alley?", "answer": "Barney's Bowl-A-Rama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1a9", "question": "What is a \"rosti\"?\u00a0", "answer": "A pancake of fried grated potatoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c43", "question": "Where does Mort Goldman work in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Goldman's Pharmacy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca23", "question": "How many constellations are used in modern astronomy?", "answer": "88", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ab", "question": "What does an entomologist study?", "answer": "Insects", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a49f", "question": "The Albert Canal is located in which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d0742596a59cbdfbd37c", "question": "Who said, \"The hottest love has the coldest end\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a3", "question": "What is the term for the official record of a dog\u2019s ancestry?", "answer": "Pedigree", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ba", "question": "Which US state is directly south of Georgia?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ab", "question": "What 1972 movie revolves around the happenings at the Kit-Kat Klub?", "answer": "Cabaret", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab91", "question": "Which Empire was Cambodia once known as?", "answer": "Khmer", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd82070d0de9af39e9d469d", "question": "How much did the New York City subway cost to ride when it opened in 1904?", "answer": "5 cents", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c751", "question": "What is the minimum number of sides required to create a Polygon?", "answer": "3", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b8f", "question": "What 2004 film concerns the hometown pressure put on the high school football coach and players from Odessa, Texas?", "answer": "Friday Night Lights", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab24", "question": "What island country is located east of Mozambique?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339514", "question": "Who voiced Pinocchio in Disney's 1940 movie by the same name?", "answer": "Dickie Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b32362bbf195a31e15d73b8", "question": "What year was the character of Betty Crocker first introduced?", "answer": "1921", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3c1", "question": "Which South American country shares its name with a nut?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf5f", "question": "In which sport are banderillas used?", "answer": "Bullfighting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5b6", "question": "What hormone enables women to have a sense of smell superior to men?", "answer": "Estrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e6", "question": "Which missionary was the first European to discover Victoria Falls?", "answer": "David Livingstone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6574bae7e414034b5aedb", "question": "Where did Barack Obama teach constitutional law?", "answer": "University of Chicago", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa566cc73aa70ea0b70b2b", "question": "Which country hosts the World Ice Golf Championship?", "answer": "Greenland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133990e", "question": "Who was musical director for Johnny Carson's \"The Tonight Show\" from 1967\u00ad to 1992?", "answer": "Doc Severinsen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c88e61b22f44c2d77a29c3f", "question": "What is Patty's last name in the 1978 film \"Grease\"?", "answer": "Simcox", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff14169b0ee8c595b6d39a3", "question": "What type of painting is Johannes Vermeer's \"Girl with a Pearl Earring\"?", "answer": "Tronie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e72d074d0874f1a5e2d1c2b", "question": "In 1892, who became the first ever Pro-Football player to be paid for playing the game?", "answer": "William \"Pudge\" Heffelfinger", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eb3", "question": "What Broadway musical featured the song \"Anatevka\"?", "answer": "Fiddler on the Roof", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394de", "question": "What show was based on the novel \"Poor, Poor Ophelia\"?", "answer": "The Streets of San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb2", "question": "Golda Meir was the leader of what country?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3550ff048f679a45ab00", "question": "Which planets in our solar system have rings around them?", "answer": "Jupiter, Saturn, Neptune, and Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b077", "question": "What was the last name of Civil Rights activist Malcolm X?", "answer": "Little", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a1a", "question": "What female band had hits in the 1980\u2019s with the songs \"Cruel Summer\" and \"Venus\"?", "answer": "Bananarama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5902a125cad1ec93f27df774", "question": "What 1960\u2019s film with Michael Caine is often credited with aiding to the popularity of the French Press?", "answer": "The Ipcress File", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6017370a44491cbd7c5a1783", "question": "Hugin and Munin were raven spirits that accompanied which Nordic figure?", "answer": "The ravens Hugin and Munin (meaning \"thought\" and \"memory\") are said to sit on the shoulders of the Nordic god Odin.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec8d25ec223966ae8f884f", "question": "Who said this in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"? \"Hope is a dangerous thing. Hope can drive a man insane.\"", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69fe920565ad31a57c792", "question": "What is the oldest-known epic tale?", "answer": "\"Epic of Gilgamesh\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339419", "question": "What do the letters PJ stand for in PJ Harvey?", "answer": "Polly Jean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdff6ab1cf6db9ac4808cf0", "question": "Where is the longest freshwater beach in the world?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a664", "question": "Cape Hatteras National Seashore is located on which coast?", "answer": "Atlantic coast", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067c20ff9c0647b50a806a", "question": "What mountain range does the Gotthard Base Tunnel pass through?", "answer": "The Alps", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe1ec33145fb29466707385", "question": "What is the primary ingredient in a \"hoecake\"?", "answer": "Cornmeal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2cc", "question": "Which 1947 film, starring Cary Grant and Loretta Young was directed by Henry Koster?", "answer": "The Bishop's Wife", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad09", "question": "What was Albert Einstein's first job after graduating from Zurich Polytechnic?", "answer": "Patent clerk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2115a31a458464a93c441", "question": "Which American author was awarded both the Nobel Prize in Literature and Presidential Medal of Freedom?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbe", "question": "What model was married to musician Marilyn Manson?", "answer": "Dita Von Teese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c79efbde8045e48466c5", "question": "Studies show dogs can see which two colors?", "answer": "Dogs can make out combinations of blue and yellow, which may explain why they prefer toys in these colors.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e3", "question": "In The Simpsons, what was Maggie's first word?", "answer": "Daddy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa96", "question": "In what country is Thunder Bay?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e1", "question": "What is the name of the first book in the \"Bourne Trilogy\"?", "answer": "The Bourne Identity", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff51aebff04d658268c930a", "question": "Who kept Odysseus trapped on a remote island for seven years?", "answer": "Along his journey in \"The Odyssey\" Odysseus became trapped on the island of Ogygia as a prisoner of the goddess-nymph Calypso.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a28e", "question": "Which US band had a 1974 hit song with \"Billy Don't Be a Hero\"?", "answer": "Bo Donaldson and The Heywoods", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c47f", "question": "What are baby sharks known as?", "answer": "Pups", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b675e662d71a53651008", "question": "In which period did ballet originate?", "answer": "Italian Renaissance", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c380", "question": "What was the name of the very first space-ready shuttle?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe3eb0d38e4e5d4832e6318", "question": "What name was given to the west wind by the Greeks?", "answer": "Zephyrus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c3e9a2cebfabb9c85d8a978", "question": "Which British Prime Minister died in 1965?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c545", "question": "In which part of the body are your metatarsals located?", "answer": "Foot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b46f", "question": "Which politician is known as Tarzan?", "answer": "Michael Heseltine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6af", "question": "What do climbers rub on their hands for extra grip?", "answer": "Chalk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b2a", "question": "What 1973 horror movie features the characters Father Merrin and Father Karras?", "answer": "The Exorcist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a5f", "question": "On what thoroughfare does the Muffin Man live?", "answer": "Drury Lane", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff2574a31a458464a93c463", "question": "Which restaurant chain fooled the public on 1 April 1998 with the introduction of a fictional sandwich for left-handed people?", "answer": "Burger King released an ad for the fictitious \"Left-Handed Whopper\" on April Fool's Day of 1998.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a324", "question": "What was the full name of Mangum P.I.?", "answer": "Thomas Magnum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b0e844964118b2bb3809c4", "question": "Valentine\u2019s Day is also known as the \"Feast of\u2026\" what?", "answer": "Saint Valentine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ba", "question": "What was the name of the first album released by the 1990's German band \"Snap!\"?", "answer": "World Power", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a75", "question": "What Irish author wrote the 1938 novel \"Murphy\"?", "answer": "Samuel Beckett", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa4394c73aa70ea0b70b17", "question": "Flanders is part of which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af256b3b63e5727cf5a483f", "question": "What popular toy, that is still widely used today, was invented by Arthur K. Melin in 1958?", "answer": "The Hula Hoop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1e", "question": "If cattle are bovine, what are sheep?", "answer": "Ovine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab36", "question": "What is the capital of Cook Islands?", "answer": "Avarua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a982", "question": "Which island of Japan is just 26 miles form Russia at its closest point?", "answer": "Hokkaido", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a94", "question": "What was the title of the 2007 Larry the Cable Guy movie where he played a bumbling Army reservist?", "answer": "Delta Farce", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a40", "question": "What was the first name of the American artist \"Grandma Moses\"?", "answer": "Anna", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea3e09ff048f679a45ab58", "question": "In 1906, a call for higher vitamin intakes was made to decrease outbreaks of which ailments?", "answer": "Scurvy and Ricketts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ab1b3f44fda37788a9a1dc6", "question": "Where is the Salvador Dali museum located?", "answer": "St. Petersburg, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b7ffa193a3a814d89068c59", "question": "Who secretly married Sara Lownds in November 1965?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad1a", "question": "What is the capital of Bulgaria?", "answer": "Sofia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339565", "question": "Which child actress claimed to have stopped believing in Santa Claus when he asked for her autograph?", "answer": "Shirley Temple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e0a", "question": "In Greek myth, what nine sisters are the daughters of Mnemosyne?", "answer": "The Muses", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398f3", "question": "What is Goldfinger\u2019s first name?", "answer": "Auric", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa8a", "question": "What is the capital of Lesotho?", "answer": "Maseru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac67", "question": "Who was the first US president?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa57fbc73aa70ea0b70b37", "question": "Which U.S. state features the Italian phrase \"Fatti maschii, parole femine\" as its state motto?", "answer": "Maryland  (The motto translates as \u201cManly deeds, womanly words.\u201d\u00a0 The state uses\u00a0\"Strong deeds, gentle words\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58dba735874c93a3298b2162", "question": "A nail polish that is clear and goes on top of a colored polish is called what?", "answer": "Top coat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c620", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Carbon?", "answer": "C", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0dc", "question": "The eldest sister in the TV series \"Charmed\", was played by who?", "answer": "Shannon Doherty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f8b", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"On the Waterfront\"?", "answer": "Eva Marie Saint", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b0", "question": "What is the name of the coffee shop the \"Friends\" gang frequents?", "answer": "Central Perk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a229", "question": "What year marked the release of  Puff Daddy's song \"I'll Be Missing You\"?", "answer": "1997", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef96c16ce05a3942286ea0", "question": "What kind of sneakers did Rocky wear in his training montage?", "answer": "Chuck Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6003951257a0e35c43f83891", "question": "Any color plus white is called what?", "answer": "A tint", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133935c", "question": "In what city did the TV show \"Full House\" take place?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd662c7a5bfecdd737e0848", "question": "What was Princess Diana's title before she married Prince Charles?", "answer": "Lady Diana Spencer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c372", "question": "How many carats is pure gold?", "answer": "24", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abad", "question": "Which US state is Baltimore located in?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9386a6bd93ce3a4e5f684", "question": "What cosmologist theorized the creation of the universe from quantum fluctuations?", "answer": "Alexander Vilenkin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad3d", "question": "Which archaeologist discovered King Tut's tomb in 1922?", "answer": "Howard Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59412872bab1e6f9796f1b5d", "question": "Who composed \"Symphonie fantastique\"?", "answer": "Hector Berlioz", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b4f", "question": "Who was the son of Zeus and Maia?", "answer": "Hermes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133955c", "question": "What actor played \"Shoeless Joe\" Jackson in the movie \"Field of Dreams\"?", "answer": "Ray Liotta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad9dc69e748bb36357acddd", "question": "What 21st-century US presidential candidate had a spouse who was president of two colleges?", "answer": "Bernie Sanders", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c386", "question": "Bronze is an alloy of what two metals?", "answer": "Tin and copper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133887e", "question": "Which character do the events of the narrative's plot revolve around and with whom the audience identifies itself with?", "answer": "The Protagonist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b149", "question": "What Egyptian pharaoh was known as \"The Boy King\"?", "answer": "Tutankhamen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60136fd7138175489539637d", "question": "Nolan Bushnell, the founder of Atari, is also the founder of what restaurant chain?", "answer": "Chuck E. Cheese -- It is famous for its pizza, animatronic shows, and electronic games - a feature pioneered by Nolan Bushnell.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a162c85f01ec323f8491730", "question": "The song \"Matchmaker, Matchmaker\" came from which musical?", "answer": "Fiddler on the Roof", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b5a0e662d71a53650ffd", "question": "How did Jay Gatsby make his money in \"The Great Gatsby\"?", "answer": "Bootlegging", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69b0f20565ad31a57c75b", "question": "In Nazi concentration camps, a pink triangle signified the prisoner as what?", "answer": "Homosexual", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e6bcfe83fe1f2a824bd1", "question": "Who gave Queen Elizabeth I the soubriquet \"Gloriana\"?", "answer": "Edmund Spenser, in his epic poem \"The Faerie Queene\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c2d", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Little House on the Prairie\"?", "answer": "Laura Ingalls Wilder", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ee", "question": "What actress fell for an American reporter in the 1953 movie \"Roman Holiday\"?", "answer": "Audrey Hepburn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c49d", "question": "Self-rising flour contains what crucial ingredient?", "answer": "Baking powder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd3", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"soy\"?", "answer": "Japanese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e0", "question": "Where does SpongeBob SquarePants work?", "answer": "The Krusty Krab", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe37a840ada16518afdc05a", "question": "Who was the leader of China during World War II?", "answer": "Chiang Kai-shek", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab01", "question": "What is the capital of Honduras?", "answer": "Tegucigalpa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c71", "question": "What year was Sylvester Stallone born?", "answer": "1946", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6996320565ad31a57c745", "question": "According to the Bible, who was the father of Arphaxad?", "answer": "Shem", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59029d97cad1ec93f27df750", "question": "What company\u2019s tea shipment was destroyed during the Boston Tea Party in 1773?", "answer": "East India Company", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590681e5ff9c0647b50a8098", "question": "What fictional town is the Netflix series \"Stranger Things\" based in?", "answer": "Hawkins, Indiana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febaeee7e83c707845b20f9", "question": "What gives eyes their color?", "answer": "Melanin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5db03f91aa1c9af2684d79a7", "question": "Which college did Bill Gates drop out from?", "answer": "Harvard", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133893e", "question": "What armless statue in the Louvre is described as \"the most famous work of art of the ancient Greek sculpture\"?", "answer": "Venus de Milo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a25f1876682715b82711ce1", "question": "Pyrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef66216ce05a3942286e77", "question": "Who voiced Miss Piggy originally?", "answer": "Frank Oz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb2667e83c707845b2112", "question": "Which celestial body is known as both the morning star and evening star?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a626", "question": "Which is the westernmost state in the US?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133972e", "question": "How many husbands did Elizabeth Taylor have?", "answer": "7", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a31a", "question": "Who provided the original voice for the character of Tigger?", "answer": "Paul Winchell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c86c", "question": "What disease, caused by the bacteria Y. pestis, is spread by fleas and rats?", "answer": "Bubonic plague", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c4", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering Penicillin?", "answer": "Alexander Fleming", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af95", "question": "In what year did the Spanish Civil War begin?", "answer": "1936", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c31e", "question": "What is the name of Google's mobile operating system?", "answer": "Android", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca91", "question": "What is a \"kiwano\" a type of?", "answer": "Fruit", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b3589e25db0d66a186cb54f", "question": "French fries are claimed to have originated in which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adc3", "question": "Which country was the scene of the Mau Mau rebellion in the 1950s?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcff", "question": "What American company had a thirty-foot inflatable gorilla atop its Rhode Island offices for decades?", "answer": "Samsonite", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59774255284458f1d785441f", "question": "Who played Secret Service Agent James West in The 1966-1968 television series \"The Wild, Wild, West\"?", "answer": "Robert Conrad", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "595245b7736d4be723796b6e", "question": "The tiles used in which game have dots that are called \"Pips\"?", "answer": "Dominoes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59029feccad1ec93f27df766", "question": "What country does the cappuccino originate from?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad15", "question": "Who is the founder of Carthage?", "answer": "Dido", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa8", "question": "\"A bushy, bushy blonde hair\u00addo\" is a line from what hit song?", "answer": "Surfin' USA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea77f9ff048f679a45abd1", "question": "Which animal has a gestation period of only 12 to 14 days?", "answer": "Opossum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1de", "question": "Which US president lived in Mount Vernon?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefa4436ce05a3942286eb0", "question": "What action hero was a champion cha cha dancer?", "answer": "Bruce Lee", "category": "entertainment"}]